Guide to the Frank Altschul Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Frank Altschul Papers,
1884-1986
[Bulk: 1925-1980].
Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981.
84.2 linear ft. ( 200 document boxes, 1 oversize box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0022
4078512
This collection documents the life of Frank Altschul--investment banker, publisher, and philanthropist--through his correspondence, writing, and research.
Biographical Note
Frank Altschul was born in San Francisco on April 21, 1887 to Charles and Camilla Mandlebaum Altschul. Charles, a partner in the investment firm Lazard Frares, brought his family to New York City in 1901 to work at the company's New York office. Frank Altschul studied at Yale University, graduating with a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1908. Following commencement, he traveled for two years, studying banking in London, Paris, Berlin, and Mexico City. During World War I, he served as an Army captain in France and was awarded the Legion of Honor. He married Helen Lehman Goodhart in 1913, and the couple would have four children.
Altschul proved to be a highly successful financier and became a senior partner at Lazard Freres in 1943. In 1948, he became chairman of the board of the General American Investors Corporation, where he remained until his retirement in 1961. During the 1930's, Altschul also served on the governing committee of the New York Stock Exchange and was director of the Chase National Bank.
Altschul applied his skill in running large organizations to a variety of causes, particularly political and advocacy organizations. He served as Director of the English-Speaking Union and vice president of the Woodrow Wilson Foundation and was heavily involved in the Council on Foreign Relations for almost four decades, serving as secretary and later as vice president from 1951 to 1971. Altschul's interest in interntional affairs was also present in his writing. A prolific writer of essays, articles, and book reviews, as well as a book, Let No Wave Engulf Us (1944). He frequently wrote letters to the editors of major newspapers, particularly the New York Times. Altschul was invited to speak before groups ranging from political and business committees to high school classes, and gave talks on psychological warfare, US relations with Israel, and many other subjects.
A self-described bibliophile, Altschul was an avid collector of books and possessed a lifelong fascination with printing. He was the co-founder and first chairman of the Yale Library Associates, which oversees the Yale Library System the Beineke Library. He established an endowment and donated much of his own collection to the Bienecke, including an extensive collection of the works and papers of George Meredith. In 1933, Altschul founded Overbrook Press on his estate in Stamford, Connecticut and began producing a wide variety of books, pamphlets, and ephemera. The press was highly regarded for its craftsmanship and innovative design work, and Overbrook volumes were consistently included in the ''Fifty Books of the Year'' show of the American Institute of Graphic Arts. Overbrook Press was dissolved in 1969.
Altschul was a philanthropist and supporter of education and the arts, endowing chairs and fellowships at Yale, Williams College, the Mount Sinai School of Medicine and the New School for Social Research. He also gave generously to hospitals and charities. His wife Helen shared his interest in education, serving on the board of trustees Barnard College and funding a chair in English.
Frank Altschul died on May 29, 1981.
Scope and Content
The collection documents Altschul's personal life and his ventures into publishing, politics, and international affairs. It contains little material directly related to his banking career. The bulk of the files contain correspondence, drafts and discussions of Altschul's writings; administrative files from his positions in various organizations; and pamphlets, articles and brochures on subjects which interested him. It also holds smaller amounts of photographs and memorabilia, as well as writings and notes by his father, Charles Altschul, and other family members and associates.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into eight series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1884-1986
Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence, 1884-1978
Subseries I.2: General Correspondence, 1906-1986
Series II: Charles and Camilla Altschul Files, 1909-1930
Series III: Writings by Frank Altschul and Others, 1910-1974
Series IV: Subject and Political Files, 1919-1979
Subseries IV.1: Subject Files, 1919-1979
Subseries IV.2: Political Files, 1932-1978
Series V: Printed Materials, 1909-1984
Series VI: Photographs, circa 1920-1960
Series VII: Memorabilia, 1914-1916
Series VIII: Organizations, 1908-1983
Subjects
Herbert H. Lehman Collections (Columbia University); American Jewish Committee.; Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.; Columbia University.; Council on Foreign Relations.; National Planning Association.; Woodrow Wilson Foundation.; Yale University.; Altschul, Charles, 1857-1927.; Altschul, Camilla.; Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.; Lehman, Herbert H., Mrs.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; New York (N.Y.); International relations.; Book collecting.; Disarmament.; Humanitarianism.; Political campaigns.; Printing.; World War, 1914-1918.; Cold War.; Photoprints.; Bankers.; Philanthropists.; Book collectors.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1980 M-37 Gift
Gift of Frank Altschul, 1980.
Related Material
Overbrook Press Records, 1929-1978 Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Herbert H. Lehman Papers, 1858-1963 Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
The International Institute of Rural Reconstruction Records, 1914-1999 Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Finding Aid available in repository and online; folder level control.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1884-1986
  This series is divided into two subseries, Cataloged Correspondence and General Correspondence.
  - Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence, 1884-1979
    This subseries is composed of correspondence between Altschul and prominent businessmen, artists, and political figures, including Alfred Knopf, Henry Kissinger, and Herbert H. Lehman. The files were originally part of General Correspondence, but have been removed and cataloged separately. They are arranged alphabetically by correspondent name.
    - Abzug, Bella, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1953-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adler, Elmer, 1923-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Agar, Herbert, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1931-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alphand, Herve, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alsop, Joseph, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alsop, Stewart, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Angell, Norman, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Armstrong, Hamilton, 1926-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Astor, Nancy, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Attlee, Clement, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Austin, Warren, 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baker, Howard, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Balwin, Raymond, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Barton, Bruce, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Barzun, Jacques, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Battle, George, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Ben-Gurion, David, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Berle, Adolph, 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bernays, Edward, 1934-1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1933-1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bowles, Chester, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bradley, Omar, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brewster, Kingman, 1964-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brzezinski, Zbingniew, 1961-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Buckley, James, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Buckley, William F., 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bundy, McGeorge, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bush, Prescott, 1945-1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Byrd, Harry, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Callaghan, James, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Canfield, Cass, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Carey, Hugh, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Castle, William R., 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cerf, Bennett, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chadbourne, William, 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Church, Frank, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Lucius D, 1956-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cleland, Thomas, 1935-1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Cohn, Alfred E., 1931-1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Coolidge, Archibald C, 1921-1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1945-1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Cox, Archibald, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Curie, Eve, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cushing, Harvey, 1927-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Davis, John W, 1921-1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Dewey, Thomas, 1938-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Dodd, Thomas J, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Donovan, William J, 1938-1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Douglas, Lewis, 1947-1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Dryfoos, Orvil E., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Duggan, Stephen, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Dulles, Allen and Clover, 1938-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1930-1947 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Durant, Will, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Earle, Edward, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Eban, Abba, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Emmett, Burton, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Ervin, Sam, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Farley, James, 1942-1951 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Finletter, Thomas K, 1958-1960 (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 38 to 39)
    - Finletter, Thomas U, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Flagler, Harry, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Flanders, Ralph, 1939-1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Florinsky, Michael, 1932-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ford, Guy, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Frank, Glenn, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Frederica, Queen of Greece, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Fulbright, J. William, 1955-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Galantiere, Lewis, 1952-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Galbraith, John K, 1948-1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Gibbings, Robert, 1925-1931 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Gill, Brendan, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Goodman, Benny, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Green, Marshall, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Grasso, Ella, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Grew, Joseph, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Gruening, Ernest, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gunther, John, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Halifax, Earl of, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hanks, Nancy, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Hard, William, 1937-1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1953-1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Heckscher, August, 1932-1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Heckscher, August and Claude, 1952-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hersey, John, 1965-1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Herter, Christain 1943-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Herzog, Yaacov, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hill, Lister, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Hilles, Charles, 1936-1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Hiss, Alger, 1947-1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Holt, Hamilton, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1953-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hutton, E.F., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Isaacs, Stanley, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jackson, Barbara, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Jackson, Henry, 1947-1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Jameson, J. Frank, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Javits, Jacob, 1949-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1948-1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Johnson, Lyndon, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Kahn, Herman, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Kempner, Marshall, 1952-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Kennan, George F., 1947-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Kennedy, John F, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Kennerly, Mitchell, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Keynes, John M., 1920-1932 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Kinstler, Everett, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Kirk, Grayson, 1947-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Koch, Edward I., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1954-1978 (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Knopf, Alfred, 1941-1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Laguardia, Fiorello, 1937-1941 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Lamont, Thomas, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Landon Alf, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Lane, Margaret, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Leffingwell, R., 1926-1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lehman, Edith A., 1965-1971 (6 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 7 to 13)
    - Lehman, Edith A., 1972-1976 (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Lehman, Herbert, 1928-1964 (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Lehman, Herbert, undated (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Lehman, Irving, 1932-1949 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lerner, Max, 1943-1951 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lewisohn, Sam, 1932-1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lindsay, John, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Lodge, Henry C., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Long, Russell, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Luce, Clare B., 1933-1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Luce, Henry, 1939-1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - MacDonald, Jean, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - McDonald, James G., 1925-1947 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - McGovern, George, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - MacLaine, Shirley, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - MacMillan, Harold, 1962-1969 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Macy, George, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Malik, Charles, 1951-1961 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Mansfield, Howard, 1924-1931 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Mansfiels, Mike, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Meir, Golda, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Mondale, Walter, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Montague, Gilbert, 1947-1960 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Morgenthau, Henry, 1933-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Morgenthau, Robert, 1969-1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Morse, Wayne, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Moses, Robert, 1942-1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1947-1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1952-1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1948-1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Nitze, Paul, 1954-1974 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Ogburn, Charlton, 1946-1962 (4 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 10 to 13)
    - Paley, William, 1939-1964 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Pepper, Claude, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Pichon, Leon, 1919-1956 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Plimpton, Francis, 1961-1967 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Pope, Arthur, 1942-1948 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Prescott, Orville, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Proskauer, Joseph, 1932-1967 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Reid, Whitelaw, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Reston, James, 1948-1972 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1952-1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Rockefeller, David, 1947-1978 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Rockefeller, Laurance, 1961-1971 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1956-1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Rogers, Bruce, 1934-1945 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Rogers, Lindsay, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D, 1932-1943 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Roper, Elmo, 1949-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Ross, Roger, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Rudge, William, 1922-1932 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Ruml, Beardsley, 1945-1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1955-1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Saltonastall, Leverett, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Sarnoff, David, 1939-1969 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Schary, Dore, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, 1952-1967 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Seligman, Eustace, 1940-1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Seligman, Eustace, 1959-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Seymour, Charles, 1923-1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Seymour, Whitney, 1952-1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Shotwell, James, 1918-1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Sloan, Alfred, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Margaret, 1953-1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Snow, C.P., 1963 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Standard, Paul, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Stern, Isaac, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 1954-1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur, 1931-1975 (Box 11, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1935-1958 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Symington, Stuart, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Symons, A.J.A., 1929-1931 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Szilard, Leo, 1955-1961 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Taft, Charles, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Taft, Robert, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Taylor, Maxwell, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Teller, Edward, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1960-1964 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Truman, Harry, 1945-1963 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Tyson, Levering, 1952-1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Updike, John, 1930-1932 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Uris, Leon, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Van Doren, Irita, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Voorhees, Tracy, 1953-1974 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Warburg, Felix, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Wagner, Robert F., 1955-1964 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Wardwell, Allen, 1932-1944 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Wechsler, James, 1953-1970 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Weiker, Lowell, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Welles, Sumner, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Wilkie, Wendell, 1939-1944 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Wilmot, John, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Wood, C.E.S., 1927-1929 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Young, Owen, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Zola, Emile, 1884 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Subseries I.2: General Correspondence, 1906-1986
    This series contains extensive files of correspondence relating to Altschul's personal life and the many activities he pursued outside of his banking career. It includes discussions with scientists, historians, and others about political events and theories, conversations with editors about article drafts and reviews, congratulatory notes and holiday cards, and intimate letters between friends and family members. Files include both incoming correspondence and copies of outgoing letters by Altschul and his secretary. They are arranged alphabetically, with some further division by document type.
    - Abram, Morris, 1965-1971 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Ad-Als (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Alexander, Henry Clay and Annalita (Formerly Marsighli), 1965-1976 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Altschul, Arthur, 1931-1978 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Altschul, Charles II, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Altschul, Edith, 1930-1933 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Altschul, Ernst, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Altschul, Frank, 1933-1974
      - Outgoing Correspondence, 1933-1944 (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Birthday Acknowledgements, 1957-1967 (4 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 5 to 8)
      - Honorary Degree and Accident (A-J), 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Honorary Degree and Accident (J-Z), 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Wedding Anniversaries, 1963-1974 (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Birthday Acknowledgements, 1968-1974 (7 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 4 to 10)
      - Award from Columbia University, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Hospitalization Correspondence, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Birthday Acknowledgements, 1975-1977 (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Altschul, and Helen Goodhart Altschul, 1920s-1930s (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Altschul, Helen Goodhart, 1962-1973
      - Birthdays, 1962-1973 (5 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 5 to 9)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Family, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Altschul, Julius, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Altschul, Margaret, 1932-1934 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Altschul, Richard, 1923-1927 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Altschul, Rosita, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Altschul, Stephanie Wagner, 1961 (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Altschul, William 1927-1930 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Am-Aus, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish and Christa, 1947-1974 (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Arnstein, Lawrence 1952-1962, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Arnstein, Lawrence, 1962-1979, (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Arnstein, Margaret (Peg), 1957-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bab-Bal (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ballantine, Arthur, Helen and Family, 1947-1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Bar-Boy (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Bararch, Alvan and Frederica, 1950-1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Benton, William A., 1940-1973, (5 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Bingham, Jonathon, 1966-1977 (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Bloch, Laine and Jean F, 1935-1951 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Boardman, Harry, 1972-1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Boardman, Wendy, 1973-1979 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Bra-Burr (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Brand, Robert H., 1937-1963 (4 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 7 to 10)
    - Brand, Thomas and Leila, 1939-1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bridges, Styles, 1946-1954 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Bruce, James, 1944-1977 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Buell, Raymond L., 1942-1944 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Burden, William A.M. and Margaret, 1956-1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Ca-Ch, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Chiaramonte, Mildred, 1948-1974 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Churchill, Mary H., 1941-1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Cl (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Cleland, Thomas Maitland, 1960-1964 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Coh-Coo (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Coltelloni, Paul and Yvonne, 1938-1945 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Condlife, John and Jane, 1949-1958 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Cor-Cou (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Cousins, Norman, Ellen and Family, 1945-1973 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Cr-Day, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Davenport, Russell, 1940-1950 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - David-Weill, David, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - David-Weill, Pierre and Berthe, 1934-1945 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Davies, John Patton, 1951-1955 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Dea-Deu (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Dean, Arthur H, 1948-1965 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - De Chambrun, Rene and Josee, 1935-1948 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Dev-Dry (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Deviak, Milorad and Deviak, Lana, 1951-1971 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Dolbeare, Frederic R., 1955-1962 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Duc-Dur (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Elliott, William Yandell, 1955-1960 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Evans, Margaret B., 1964-1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Fab-Fe (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1941-1947 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Focillon, Marguerite H., 1954-1964 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Fi-Fu, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Franchomme, Philippe and Germaine, 1937-1967 (5 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 6 to 10)
    - Freund, Arthur, 1946-1951 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Freund, Arthur, 1952-1971 (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Friedman, Elisha M., 1932-1949 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Furth, Otto and Harold, 1940-1950 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Ga-Ge (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Gaither, Rowan, 1954-1961 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Gardner, John, 1958-1973 (Box 24, Folder 8)